hey this is Bret andas uh just wanted to
show off the top squat here this is a
device that was invented by Dave Draper
he was a friend of Arnold's back in the
day a classic bodybuilder and he
invented this um as a way to perform
squats all you all you do here is just
hook it onto a
barbell and
um the reason why this is important is
because some guys over time you know
they lose external rotation mobility in
their
shoulders and they find you know back
squatting to be painful for their
shoulders it irritates their shoulders
so here's a way to do the back squat
where you have the bar right out in
front of you and so it's easier on your
shoulders so for people who can no
longer back
squat can just use the top squat just
like this you
know and it's just you know it's pretty
comfortable you just squat just like
normal just like that this
way you can keep the arms right here in
this position you don't have to crank
back into external
rotation
so anyway it's nice and comfortable
light and compact as you can see this is
is all you have to do you could carry it
with you to the gym but for certain
people who have given up back squatting
because of shoulder issues this offers a
good alternative